MOHAMMAD RICKO APRILIANTO

Kalimantan Selatan • ricko.apriliantooo@gmail.com • +62 819-3243-2218 linkedin.com/in/mohammadrickoaprilianto • github.com/rickosong

Profile Summary

I'm Mohammad Ricko Aprilianto, a Digital Business student and a tech enthusiast with a focus on Web and Mobile Development especially in Backend Development. Beyond coding, I also explore Digital Marketing. I can work well in team and have a commitment to continuous learning, always trying to improve my technical and soft skills.

Skills

Programming

- Kotlin
- PHP, Laravel
- JavaScript, JQuery
- Python, Django

Specialized Skills

- Web Development
- Mobile Development (Android)
- Digital Marketing
- Project Management

Education

Politeknik Negeri Banjarmasin

Aug 2022 - Current

Bachelor of Applied Digital Business - IPK 3.86

SMKN 2 Banjarmasin

Jul 2019 - May 2022

High School Diploma of Computer Software Engineering - Score 87.98

Experience

Freelance Mobile Developer

Dec 2024

- Independently developed a mobile application using Kotlin.
- Designed the application architecture and implemented both front-end and back-end features.
- Handled database management.

Mobile Developer Learning Path — Bangkit Academy led by Google, GoTo, & Traveloka

Sep 2024 - Dec 2024

- Selected as one of 4,000 participants from over 100,000 applicants for the Kampus Merdekacertified Bangkit Academy.
- Completed curated modules in Android development using Kotlin, software engineering fundamentals, Git & GitHub, and app deployment.

- Participated in industry-standard training including soft skills, English communication, and product-based capstone project development.
- Collaborated in a team project to build a tech solution for real-world problems in Indonesian society.

Freelance Web Developer

Aug 2022 - Sep 2022

- Collaboratively planned application architecture with a team using React and Tailwind CSS for front-end development.
- Developed the Back-End using the Laravel framework.
- Handled deployment and database management.

SMKN 2 Banjarmasin

Nov 2021 - Dec 2021

Web Developer

- Contributed to infrastructure website (Pusat Pelayanan Lansia) development by planning application architecture with a team.
- Developed the website using Wordpress.
- Utilized Elementor for the front-end.
- Managed deployment and databases.

PT. Digiclass Indonesia International

Aug 2021 - Dec 2021

Digital Marketer

- Conducted keyword research to identify high-traffic, relevant keywords to target in content and campaigns.
- Analyzed search trends to find new content opportunities.
- Utilized SEO tools like Google Trends and Keyword Tool io to find effective keywords.
- Created engaging and informative content.
- Produced visual content such as infographics, videos, and images to support marketing strategies.
- Managed content posting schedules across various social media platforms including Facebook, Instagram, LinkedIn, and Youtube.
- Monitored and analyzed website performance using tools like Google Analytics.
- Teaching digital marketing to a newly hired intern.

Certification

Certificate of Completion - Mobile Development

Bangkit led by Google, Goto, and Traveloka

KMIPN V - E-Government - Finalist

Politeknik Elektronika Negeri Surabaya

Itech Poliban Competition - Software Development - Second Place *Itech Poliban*

Level II KKNI Certification Scheme At the Competence of Software Engineering Skills

Badan Nasional Sertifikasi Profesi (BNSP)

Provincial Level Web Technologies Skills Competition (LKS) - Third Place $\it LKS\,SMK$

Digital Marketing Competency Certification

Badan Nasional Sertifikasi Profesi (BNSP)